A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Special Events and Activities, Anti-Vivisection Activities FA142
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Special Events and Activities, Anti-Vivisection Activities
1908-1911
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Rockefeller University
FA142
8.16 Cubic Feet 23 document boxes.
23 document boxes.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 600-1
Arrangement
Alphabetical
Scope and Contents
Types of records include: correspondence, clippings, and printed material.
Cell and biomolecular sciences; Biology -- Research; Medical sciences; Vivisection; Genetics; China; Medicine, Preventive; Medical research; Medical care; DNA; MacLeod, Colin M. (Colin Munro); McCarty, Maclyn; Avery, Oswald Theodore; Seitz, Frederick
- Anti-vivisection Activities, 1908-1911; 1
  - "Ammunition" (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bradshaw, William R. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - British Union for the Abolition of Vivisection, The British Anti-vivisection Society (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Defense of Research" pamphlets (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lind-af-Hageby, Louise (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Medical Society of the State of New York (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Noguchi, Hideyo (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General correspondence, 1908-1914 (Box 1, Folder 8-11)
  - "Hearing... 15 Feb 1915", 1915 February 15 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - General correspondence, 1915-1930 (Box 1, Folder 13-23)
  - General correspondence, 1930-1950 (Box 2, Folder 1-17)
  - General correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Hearing... 24 March 1909", 1909 March 24 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "Proceedings of meeting... 25 Feb 1910", 1910 February 25 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "Hearing... 8 Mar 1911", 1911 March 8 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - "Hearing... 18 Feb 1913", 1913 February 18 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - American Anti-Vivisection Society (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - American Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Boy Scouts of America (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Committee for the Protection of Animal Experimentation (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - New York Antivivisection Society (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - New York, City of. Department of Health, Weekly Bulletins (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - New York, State of. Medical Society. "Dogs, Drugs, and Doctors", 1946 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - New York, State of. Acts (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - New York, State of. Department of Health "Rules", 1947 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - New Jersey, State of. Acts (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Society for the Prevention of Abuse in Animal Experimentation (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Vivisection Investigation League (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous printed matter, 1901-1922 (Box 3, Folder 11-23)
  - Miscellaneous printed matter, 1923-1925 undated (Box 4, Folder 1-5)
  - Miscellaneous brochures (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - "Rules regarding animals" [signed "Director of the Laboratory"] (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, 1921 1944-1952 undated (Box 4, Folder 8-14)
  - Anti-Vivisection
    Scope and Contents note
    Folder titles copied from original folders. Includes:
    - Anti-Vivisection - Arthur Brisbane (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Anti-Vivisection - Frederic S. Lee, 1911-1913 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Anti-Vivisection - Hon. Frank M. Loomis (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Anti-Vivisection - Hon. John J. McInerney (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Anti-Vivisection - Lewis K. Neff (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Anti-Vivisection - Dr. William H. Park (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Anti-Vivisection - Franklin D. Roosevelt (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Anti-Vivisection - Dr. Henry Larned Keith Shaw (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Anti-Vivisection - Dr. Wisner R. Townsend (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Anti-Vivisection - "Hoey Bill" (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Anti-Vivisection - Hon. Anthony J. Griffin. "Bayne Bill" and "Griffin Bill" in Senate (Box 5, Folder 11)
      Correspondence with: Hon. Howard R. Bayne, Hon. Edgar T. Brackett, Hon. Loring M. Black Jr., Hon. George H. Cobb, Hon. Robert H. Gittins, Hon. Anthony J. Griffin, Hon. Harvey D. Hinman, Mr. E. Mark Houghton, Hon. John Lord O'Brien, Hon. Henry W. Pollock, Hon. Alfred E. Smith, Hon. Eugene M. Travis, Dr. A. Vander Veer, Hon. Robert F. Wagner, Mr. E.S. Webster, Stenographer Senate Chamber
    - Anti-Vivisection - Investigation League (Box 5, Folder 12)
      Also Journal of Zoöphily and Dr. Keen and Dr. Noguchi
    - Anti-Vivisection - General, 1910-1913 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Anti-Vivisection - Miscellaneous Literature (Folder 1) (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Anti-Vivisection - Miscellaneous Literature (Folder 2) (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Anti-Vivisection - "Barnes Bill" (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Anti-Vivisection - Publicity (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Anti-Vivisection - Society for the Prevention of Abuse in Animal Experimentation (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Anti-Vivisection - S.P.C.A. (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Anti-Vivisection Correspondence
    Correspondence primarily with Henry James, some with Jerome D. Greene, Simon Flexner and John D. Rockefeller Jr.
    Arrangement note
    Arranged in alphabetical order.
    - A and B (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Mrs. Richard Aldrich, Dr. John Anderson, Raymond H. Arnot, Ernest Harold Baynes, Edward F. Bigelow, Mrsx Joseph A. Bryant, Mr. L.G. Brabrook, H.B. Brougham
    - C and D (Box 6, Folder 2)
      Cannon, W.B., Mrs. Charlotte Reeve Conover, Floyd M. Crandall, Miss Sarah M. Cleghorn, T. Wood Clarke, T.O.H. Cosgrave, Caroline Deming Camp, Henry S. Drinker Jr.
    - E and F (Box 6, Folder 3)
      James Ewing, Simon Flexner
    - G and H (Box 6, Folder 4)
      L.J. Gillespie, [Name?], Harvey R. Gaylord, Dr. Goldwater, HARPER'S WEEKLY, John Grier Hibben, L. Emmett Holt
    - I-J-K (Box 6, Folder 5)
      W.W. Keen
    - L and M (Box 6, Folder 6)
      Frederic S. Lee, Paul A. Lewis
    - N-O-P (Box 6, Folder 7)
      NATUROPATH MAGAZINE (w/Valdemar Blad), Niesser, Albert, Northrup Wm. P., Paget, Stephen (Research Defense Society), Park, William H., Pearce, Richard M., Pinchot, Gifford, Pearson, Frederick
    - R-S-T (Box 6, Folder 8)
      Research Defense Society, R.S. Richardson, G. Canby Robinson, Arthur S. Rosenfeld, P.S. Ridsdale, Ernest Schaeffle, J.H. Schuck, J.J. Shirley, George H. Simmons, W.P. Spangenberg, Sullivan and Cromwell, J.E. Sweet, Edgar James Swift, John S. Thacher, Wisner R. Townsend, E.L. Trudeau
    - W (Box 6, Folder 9)
      J. Henry Wallis (Walters), J. Henry Walters, M.H. Ware, Richard Welling, J.V.B. Wicoff
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Includes: Correspondence (some holograph commenting notes by Simon Flexner) and other items.
  - Clippings, 1913 December 8; 4 pp typescript (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Extracts from report given at Anti-Vivisection Congress, sent by Dr. John F. Anderson.
  - Legislation
    The following folder titles have been copied from original folders.
    - Legislative matters - New Jersey, 1914 February-1917 March (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Includes correspondence with Henry James and Simon Flexner, 1914 Feb to 1917 Mar. Also includes (2) copies of 1868 Act to incorporate N.J. Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals and other New Jersey Senate and Assembly bills
    - [Folder label missing] correspondence re legislation, State of New York, 1913-1914 1917 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - [Folder label missing] correspondence etc. re legislation, State of California, 1915 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      Includes letters by George E. Hale, Frederic S. Lee, and G.H. Whipple.
    - [Folder label missing] correspondence etc. re proceedings against Dr. Richard M. Pearce, Dr. Joshua E. Sweet of Philadelphia, 1914-1916 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - [Folder label missing] correspondence etc re legislation, Pennsylvania, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - [Folder label missing] miscellany re legislation, Pennsylvania, circa 1913-1915 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - "Legislative matters. NY" miscellany, circa 1914-1917 1925 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - "Publicity" miscellany, circa 1913-1914 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - "New York State Supreme Court... Harvey Moran against David H. Shelling. Record on Appeal", circa 1927 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - [From envelope marked "Defense of Research Material"] printed pamphlets (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - [From envelope marked "Miscellaneous Pamphlets Once Selected by Dr. Rous"] printed pamphlets, 2 folders (Box 7, Folder 6-7)
    - [Folder unlabeled] printed pamphlets, 1910 1918 1921 1926 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - "Vivisection. Hearing before the Senate Committee on the District of Columbia, February 21, 1900..." (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous printed material (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous printed material, 2 folders (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - The Open Door, 1919-1923 1925-1927; 8 folders (Box 8, Folder 3-10)
  - Anti-vivisection publications, 5" letter
    Duplicate and Triplicate copies of some issues.
    - Journal of Zoöphily, 1912-1919; 2 folders
      Published under the auspices of the American Anti-Vivisection Society, combined with the Women's Pennsylvania Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals.
      - 1912 November-December 1913 February 1913 August-September 1914 April 1914 June-August 1914 October-November 1915 March (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - 1915 April 1916 February 1916 April-May 1916 July-August 1916 December 1917 January 1917 May 1917 October 1918 July 1918 October 1918 December 1919 February (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - The Starry Cross. (formerly Journal of Zoöphily), 2 folders
      - 1919 March-December 1920 January-February 1920 April (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - 1920 May-July 1920 September-October 1920 December 1921 January-February 1921 May-June 1922 April 1922 June (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - The Open Door. The National Anti-Vivisection Magazine, 7 folders
      - 1911 August 1911 October-December 1912 January-May 1912 July-September 1912 December 1913 January-February (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - 1913 March-December 1914 January-February 1914 April-May 1914 July (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - 1914 August-September 1914 November (no 3-4) 1914 December 1915 May-August 1915 October-November (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - 1915 December 1916 January-March 1916 May 1916 August 1916 October-December 1917 January-May (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - 1917 June-August 1917 October-December 1918 January-February 1918 April-July 1918 October-December (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - 1928 January-June (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - 1933 February-March 1933 May-July 1934 March (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Our Dumb Animals. Published by The Massachusetts Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals, 3 folders
      - 1922 July-September 1922 November-December 1923 January-April 1923 July-September (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - 1923 October-December 1924 January-July 1927 May 1927 October (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - 1927 November-December-1928 January-September (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Anti-Vivisection and Defense of Research, 5" letter GL 9/86
    Printed material, pamphlets and clippings
    Includes:
    - W.B. Cannon, "The Opposition to Medical Research", 1908 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - "President Taft and the Medical Profession." Pamphlets, 1911 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Lecture courses by Georgetown University School of Medicine on animal experimentation. "A Vindication of Vivisection". Pamphlets, 1920 1922 1923 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Animal experimentation literature, 1945-1946 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Anti-vivisection and defense of research, 2 folders
      Miscellaneous publications. Includes pamphlets, printed material and clippings. Some in duplicate.
      - [undated] 1896 1908-1909 1911 1913-1914 circa 1916 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - circa 1919 1920-1922 1924-1927 1938 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Defense of Research and Anti-Vivisection Publications, Printed material and publications. 3 - 5" letter size boxes. GL 9/86
    Some duplicates. In alphabetical order by institution issuing publication, or journal publishing it.
    - American Anti-Vivisection Society, 1912 undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Includes: Henry J. Bigelow, "Vivisection" Undated. [Written just before Dr. Bigelow's death].
    - American Humane Association, 1895 1903 undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - American Medical Association, 1908 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - W.B. Cannon, "The Opposition to Medical Research", 1908 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - S.J. Meltzer, "Ideas and Ideals in Medicine", 1908 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - American Medical Association (AMA). Defense of Research Pamphlets, circa 1909-circa 1914; 3 folders (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Pamphlet I - X (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Pamphlet XI - XIX, lacking XX (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Pamphlet XXI - XXVII (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - American Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals, 1910 1914-1915 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      Annual reports and Bulletins.
    - The Boston Medical and Surgical Journal, 1923 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Djurens Rätt. Affaren Carrel, 1913. (In Swedish) (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Humane Society of New York. 1914 - 1916 Annual reports (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Journal of the American Medical Association (JAMA), 1901 1908 1923 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Medical Research Council (London), 1927 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Metropolitan Life Insurance Co. (Box 13, Folder 1)
      Includes: Statistical Bulletins 1928-1938
      - Statistical Bulletins, 1928-1938
      - Miscellaneous, undated 1931-1935
    - New York Anti Vivisection Society (Box 13, Folder 2)
      Includes: Pamphlets, Illustrations and printed materials.
    - New York State Journal of Medicine (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Flexner, Simon. The Medical Profession of the State and the Antivivisection Agitation, 1911
      - Cannon, W.B. Animal Experimentation and Its Benefits to Mankind, 1912
    - Quest. Against Vaccination and Cruel Vivisection, 1926 December (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Research Defense Society: Report of Inaugural Meeting, 19 June 1908 of Research Defense Society and miscellaneous printed material, 1908 June 19 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Research Defense Society (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - Membership lists, 1908 1909
      - Lists of officers, 1914 1916
    - Research Defense Society: printed pamphlets, 1908-1913 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Research Defense Society, 1914 1916 1920-1922 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      Printed pamphlets
      - Quarterly Journal of the Research Defense Society, 1929-1933 1935 1937
    - "Experiments on Living Animals" printed under authority of His Majesty's Stationery Office, London. [Not by Research Defense Society], 1913 August (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Research Defense Society, 1910 1912-1916 1919 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      Includes: Notices of meetings.
      Quarterly Reports.
      Annual Reports.
      Committee Reports.
      List of publications of 1912.
    - Issued by Research Defense Society. Photographs of Lord Lister and L. Pasteur (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Society for the Prevention of Abuse in Animal Experimentation. Report, 1907-1909 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Society of Friends of Medical Progress (Box 14, Folder 6)
      Includes: Printed pamphlets:
      Why It Was Founded.
      Some Recent Opinions on Modern Vivisection by Competent Living Authorities.
      Ernest Harold Baynes, "Vivisection and Modern Miracles" and "Vivisection and Animal Welfare."
      Smallpox.
    - University of Pennsylvania, 1914 printed pamphlet re. Relative to work in the department of medicine involving animal experimentation (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Vivisection Investigation League, circa 1928 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Vivisection Reform Society, 1907 1909 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Anti-Vivisection material, 1930s; 2½" letter GL 9/86
    Primarily 1930's. Includes:
    - S[imon] Flexner statement before Codes Committee at hearing of A-V (Anti-Vivisection) Bill, Feb 9, 1932, of New York State Legislature, Albany, New York, 1932 February; 3 pp typescript (carbon copy) (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Conferences, conversations (notes on) by P.[eyton] Rous, 1932 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - w/Bayne-Jones, 1932 March 18
      - w/Dr. Flexner, Dr. Flexner and Dr. Sondern, 1932 April 6
      - w/Dr. Sondern, 1932 April 8
      - w/Dr. Sondern, 1932 May 16
      - w/Dr. Sondern, 1932 June 28
      - w/Dr. Sondern, 1932 September 14
      - w/S.F. [Simon Flexner], 1932 September 20
      - Dr. Flexner w/Dr. Sondern and Dr. Rous (2 versions), 1932 September 28
    - H.R. Bill 7884. [re] defeat of bill to prohibit experiments on living dogs in the District of Columbia, 1929-1931 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      Selected items:
      - Printed copy of bill
      - Note on meeting of New York Academy of Medicine Antivivisection Committee, 1930 November 20; Typescript
      - Form letter sent by Peyton Rous to all members of House Committee of the District of Columbia as President, Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine and as a Member, NAS re defeat of Bill H.R. 7884 w/ replies from some, 1931 January 8
      - Correspondence of Peyton Rous (as member of Committee on animal experimentation of the New York Academy of Medicine) re defeat of bill, 1930-1931
        Exchange with following (includes copies of correspondence with others) John J. Abel, George Baehr, W.B. Cannon, A.J. Carlson, Rufus Cole, E.H.L. Corwin, E.C. Cutler, Joseph Erlanger, Simon Flexner, H.T. Karsner, V. Kellog, G.M. Kober, B.E. Livingston, E.P. Lyon, Wm. Welch. Includes handwritten letters' by Welsh and Rous., G. Whipple, J.L. Whitely, H. Williams, M.C. Winternitz.
    - Activities of Antivivisection Societies, reports of visits to A-V meetings and reports of meetings (Box 15, Folder 4)
      Kept in order found. Includes:
      - Activities of various anti-vivisection Societies, 1908 1914 1916 1931-1933 undated
        Includes printed and duplicated copies of correspondence, extracts from articles, excerpts from news articles.
      - Reports of visits to A-V meetings, 1930-1932
      - Reports of A-V meetings, 1930-1932
    - Copies of letters sent to members of Committee on Codes in the New York Assembly expressing opposition to Vaughn Bill, 1932 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      Includes: Letters sent by Chairman of Committee on Medical Research requesting expressions of opposition to the Vaughn Bill. Letters from members of Committee on Medical Research and Officers of other Committees of Medical Society of the State of New York. Letters from Presidents and Secretaries of County Medical Societies. Letters from Officers of Institutions and Members of the Faculties of Medical Schools in New York State. Letters from Health Officers. Letters sent by Members of New York State Association of Public Health Laboratories. Letters from Lawyers. Miscellaneous letters from Rochester Chamber of Commerce and from individuals.
    - Collection of material by P. Rous, 1933-1934 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      Perhaps useful for hearings in 1932-1936.
      - Correspondence and extracts
      - Notes
      - "Provisions of the Laws of the Various States, Great Britain, New South Wales, Victoria and Western Australia, Relative to Vivisection". Prepared by Wm. E. Hannan, Legislative Reference Librarian, New York State Library, 1933 September; 25 pp.
      - News clippings
      - Bulletin #3 from Medical Society of the State of New York, 1934 January 25; Duplicated copy
      - "Two indictments brought by the Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals", undated
  - Anti-Vivisection Activities. Miscellaneous, 5" letter GL 9/86
    - Vivisection, anti-vivisection (Box 16, Folder 1)
      Miscellaneous material. Includes:
      - Correspondence with Henry James, Business Mgr., RIMR and Medical Society of State of New York, 1913-1915
        Includes list of Secretaries of County Societies of the Medical Society of State of New York for mailing.
      - Assorted printed material
        - The Reality of Human Vivisection: A review of Dr. Keen's letter, (late President of the American Medical Association), 1901; reprint
        - Newspaper and magazine clippings, originals and photocopies re/by Simon Flexner about treatment of animals used for research at RIMR and accomplishments, 1909-1910
        - Dr. Pasteur Vallery-Radot. The Logical Sequence of Pasteur's Work. (Resume of the Lecture at RIMR on May 10, 1935), 1935 May 10; reprint
        - Undated printed pamphlets, and 1957 exchange between D.W. Bronk / W.R. Flinn re National Humane Society, 1957 undated
    - Affidavits. By RIMR scientific staff and others, 1910 January (Box 16, Folder 2)
      Includes notes by Simon Flexner. Affidavits by: Tessie Butler, Alexis Carrel, Emil Clausnitzer, Tom Horton, P.A. Levene, Katharine Lilly, S.J. Meltzer. Includes handwritten copy by Meltzer., Eugene L. Opie, Max Sloman,
      Partial affidavit, page 1 and 2 lacking, by RIMR scientific staff re Mrs. Kennedy's affidavit.
      Note in front of partial affidavit "VIVISECTION Original affidavits of certain members of the staff of The Rockefeller Institute were taken by Mr. Jerome D. Greene March 2, 1912. Initialed "M.L.N"
    - Newspaper clippings re RIMR and anti-vivisectionists. Includes photocopies. re RIMR, handwritten notes and comments w/ Mrs. Kennedy's and Mr. Dutton's affidavits and Mr. Smith's deposition, 1907 1909-1910 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper clippings re Princeton, 1914 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Defense of Research Pamphlets 1-27 (AMA) and New York Medical Society Animal Experimentation Pamphlets re animal research, 2 folders
      Appears to be maintained for Peyton Rous. Table of contents in front of each folder.
      - Defense of Research Pamphlets 1-27, 1911-1914 (Box 16, Folder 5)
        [See also: Box 12, folders 4,5,6].
      - New York Medical Society Animal Experimentation Pamphlets, 1909-1910 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Anti-Vivisection correspondence, 1930-1938; In 1 - 5" letter and 1 - 21/2" letter size boxes. GL 9/86
    Correspondence primarily with Peyton Rous; some with Simon Flexner and Herbert S. Gasser re defense of animal experimentation and medical research and its legislation for and against. Indications are that these files maintained by Dr. Peyton F. Rous as a representative of the Rockefeller Institute (RI) from 1929 on, speaking before the Codes Committee of the New York State Assembly.
    Arranged in alphabetical order by correspondent.
    - Babbott, Frank L. Jr (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Baehr, George (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Bauer, W.W. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Belais, Diana Mrs. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Benedict, William F. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Bowers, Walter P. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Bayne-Jones, S., 1931-1932 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Caldwell, Robert J. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Campion, F. Miss (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Cannon, Walter B. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Capalino, Frank (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Cattell, J. McKeen (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Chicago Daily News (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Churchman, John W. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Couturior, Jeanne Miss (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Cramp, Arthur J. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Crowden, G.P. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Cutler, Elliott C., 1930-1937 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Debevoise, Thomas M. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Dougherty, Daniel S. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Draper, George (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Carter, Celice D. (George Draper's sister) (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Drinker, Cecil K. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - re Dublin, D. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - re Miss Duncan (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Esmond, Burton D., 1931 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Flexner, Simon, 1931-1937 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Gager, C. Stuart (Box 17, Folder 8)